welcome back
today we are going to sift through the UMV tier
however before doing any of that
we have to fix our power production
while it looks like we are doing fine
we are actually not
our wireless network is indeed empty
so empty that our plasma mixer can't work
it just received 10 minutes of stocked up power
but it is draining it in no time
so we should build a second Dyson sphere
since it won't be the last one
and each one requires many different parts
we shall make a custom AE2 pattern
to prepare all of its components with a single click
and there
we have the total cost of each of those structures
once the structure is built
we can go back to our base
and remember that
we can also turn on our backup generators
to get an extra kick
sadly
we didn't hit the 1 trillion production milestone
fear not
that was the end of the fuels
but there is still more room in the future
and with the future of fuels
we can almost double the milestone
now that we have some more energy to work with
we can start our new quests
after quickly completing the usual components
we will probably want to get a component assembly line upgrade
to reduce the spacetime and hypogen costs
however
it looks like hard metals is not the thing we lack of
we are short on the polymer made by exotic bacteria
to skip the whole chemistry
we would need a tier four QFT
which however costs too many UMV components
so we go back to our clean room
where we mutate more bacteria
that we then place in some new vats
meanwhile
we can produce a couple of high tier materials
we add one more step to our circuitry
and we get the last of the UMV components
then we make the new superconductors
for the new energy hatch
which we can now make wireless
and to get this one
we had to craft all the previous wireless ones
so let's stop for a moment and go all the way back
to start off
we needed the new superconductor
which this time contains Dragon blood and space time
to make it superconducting
we can no longer use helium
space time is mandatory
but with that we only got the normal UMV energy hatch
to make it wireless
other than a bunch of expensive stuff
we need to do some research
which was recursive
all the way down to a ULV wireless energy hatch
but while we have UMV energy hatches
we don't have any ULV one
once we get it
we have to research and craft all of the other tiers
back up to UMV
and since our data bank has limited slots
and we are too lazy to make a second one
we started stocking all of the useless stuff in a chest
which is now almost full
then without any recursive research
we also acquired the most powerful wireless hatch we can make so far
UMV 64 amps
this one is as powerful as a 16,000 UV laser hatch
but wireless
and its first use should be to speed up our circuit production
so that we can make more than one UXV circuit every minute
instead of one every 15 minutes
meanwhile
we also managed to upgrade our component assembly line
the next quest isn't really a quest but a warning
we could simply Mark it as complete and move on
but I think we should upgrade our base instead
indeed as of now
we are still having trouble crafting just a couple of Dyson Spheres
that's not good at all
the first thing we will want to fix is the radox polymer production
and our main objective is to produce it with a QFT
but that requires tier 4 casings
and we have trouble even with crafting the tier 3
so we have to increase the size of our old radox setups
luckily thanks to the Loki ring
we can build many machines at the same time
and now we just have to wait a little bit
for some radox to stock up
one other thing required for the tier 4 QFT is
black body Naquadria supersolid
which is made while working Naquadria
this process outputs some inert Naquadria dusts
which may not look huge in amount
but we can expand those into thousands of ingots with a neutron activator
the only cost on conversion is a bit of plasma and time
we can shrink the time required by increasing the height of our neutron activators
and thus we shall make those pierce the sky
and that was the tier 3 QFT
for the tier 4
we need more radox polymer
while it stocks up
we can work on gathering the other materials we are short on
our old space elevator couldn't stock up enough fluids
so we upgraded its motors and its pumps
while that easily took care of the missing fluids
it won't help with the missing minerals
some ores can't be obtained by space mining
so we have to go back to void miners
but we want to place those in a more special place
the one chosen by the true edgelords like us
to get there
we have to start by compressing a lot of cobblestone
so much that we had to upgrade our explosion compressor
to space time and 8 billion EU
to get it in a reasonable amount of time
then we cover that cobblestone in cheese
which will act as glue for the other components
finally
we use magic to stick some singularities to that agglomerate
with that
we can now travel to the Promised Land
where void miners will be able to gather any ore that is shown on NEI
so we quickly get a link to the ore processing ae2 subnetwork
and start drilling all of those materials
meanwhile we have managed to complete our tier 4 QFT
which is now making huge amounts of radox polymer
now that Radox Polymer is no longer an issue
we can finally start crafting our little project of 10 Dyson Spheres
however
our current base can't handle that puny task
we must do some upgrades
the first thing we want to enchant is our blast furnaces
for some materials
they can barely cook four ingots each second
and the backlog is really huge
so after going inside and do an inspection
we decide that the best action to take
is to add some glitter to the heating coils
and then we also increase the power feed
now it works 8 times faster
the next thing we have to speed up is our fusion reactors
the Mark 3 were slow to begin with
and the Mark 4 are busy trying to make metastable oganesson
so we are going to craft the fuwusion reactor
you can already tell this is going to be way more powerful from all of its colors
and indeed it's as good as 10 of the previous tier
also for quick recipes
we can manually set the parallel counter
thus making it 100 times faster than the Mark 3
next with a thermosink radiator
we can make our PCB factory 2000 times faster
then to speed up our nanoforge
we made more of those buildings
while also increasing the working power
finally to help our DTPFs
we added four more blocks
but all of that caused a huge increase in power consumption
to help our backup generators
we increased the working efficiency
by adding two fluids
that we can obtain by tearing apart some space time using a tesseract and a quantum anomaly on an anvil
and that boost was enough to let us complete the last plasma mixer recipes
thus completing the new generators just in time before we run out of fuel
the old Dyson Spheres took quite some space
so let's try to make the new setup more compact
we figured out we can wall share a bunch of parts
the most important being the computation input
which we are now going to make wireless
thus connecting to the cloud
so that we can keep our computers in our to be data center located in our main base
with that set up
we are now producing more power
but it's still just enough for our update base
so it's clear that we are going to need more
however there is one main issue
we are too slow at producing the spiny ingots
our ebfs indeed can't even make 2 per second
and we need millions
in hope to find a solution
we shall go ask help to some random villagers
who seem to be worshipping some random deities
and it looks like our prayers got answered
all we have to do is build a forge in honor of the gods
we shall make it bigger
and more complex than any other multi block we build so far
to craft it
we are going to search unfindable particles
work weird glitchy materials
and synthesize weird stuff
once all the collection part is done
we proceed into clogging all of our whole base
to craft huge amount of all kind of things
which made us quickly cook huge amounts of old materials
and slowly chug through harder-to-work ones that required a Dyson sphere worth of power to be processed
but given enough time
we managed to process all of that stuff
and complete our new forge
and that thing isn't big just on the outside
it is also a big inside
the first thing we shall read is the nice introduction
that will explain us how that machine works
but the thing we care about the most
is the path to the celestial transcendence
this will help us upgrade our forge
furthermore
we have to start from the start if we want it to even be usable
to do this upgrade
we are going to need some additional materials
which we quickly gather and send
to complete the first upgrade
with that done
we can now add our first module
the Helioflare Power Forge
this module is going to work exactly like a blast furnace or a volcano
and now that everything is built
it is time to turn it on
to do so
we make some star fuel
and give it to our forge
then we will be supplying transcendent residue to keep it running
and thus we can now admire our forge spinning
but it's still not at the peak of its glory
indeed we can make the star on the inside more bright and colorful
and I think we can now take one good minute to admire our new machinery
and it turns out that this is not even its final form
but getting the evolution is going to be a more complex thing
so let's start by using the module we have
and we find out that this is already as good as our 8 blast furnaces together
and while that module works
we are actually increasing the progress of our forge milestones
those are goals that once reached will reward us with Graviton Shards
which can be used for more upgrades
after getting all of the basic improvements
we are faced with the first important one
this one will also require some extra materials
one of which being lossless photon transfer medium
and long story short
we are going to need to reach a temperature above anything a normal blast furnace could ever reach
17000 Kelvin
and even our helioflare struggles with that at the moment
but we can increase the fuel burn rate of our forge
to reach higher temperatures
now that we can craft those materials
we run into another issue
we don't have enough copper
but we can just pump more with the space elevator
most of that copper
is used in the production of six phased copper nanites
now while that part of the needed material takes a lot of copper
there is one other thing that instead takes a lot of time
transcendent metal nanites
so we can use that time to build more nanoforges
and with that
we have unlocked the helioflux melting core
this module will melt dusts straight into liquid
skipping the need for a vacuum freezer and a fluid extractor
with those two modules
our old blast furnaces can now go into retirement
that will drop a lot of blocks
and also destroy our unbreakable tools
which we can easily craft again
anyways
the next upgrade we can do is
the Gravitational Plasma Containment Inducer
which will unlock the Heliothermal Plasma fabricator
that thing will turn anything into plasma
now that thing is not really worth it for most of the plasma we use
but it can be a great help for some that do require some scarce materials or have low yields in the fusion reactor
it will also be the only way to obtain some peculiar plasma required later on
finally
we unlock the Heliofusion excisiter
but that is going to be used only in the next tier
and now we are stuck at the split
here we can chose only one of the three paths
while we decide which path to take
we can make the last QFTs
which will remove a lot of production chains
that will allow us to do a lot of cleanup
and refactoring of our whole base
so that we will no longer have cable messes lying around
finally
we add a bunch more of Dyson Spheres
to increase our power production
and with that
I think we are finally ready to conclude this episode
so what's the lesson today
if you want to stare at the sun
sunglasses are not enough
you need some specialized equipment
possibly a welding helmet
bye bye
欢迎回来
今天我们要进入UMV电压
然而，在做这些之前
我们必须增加发电
虽然看上去风平浪静
实则不然
无线电网可没有电
都空到不能支持蓝搅拌工作了
它才刚充了10分钟的电
就马上把它用光了
所以我们将建造第二个戴森球
由于不会是最后一个
而且每一个都需要许多不同的部分/方块
我们定制一个样板
只需单击一下即可准备其所有组件
在下单面板上
我们有这些结构的总成本
一旦结构建成
我们可以回基地了
别忘了
我们也有后备隐藏能源
来额外发电
可惜
我们的发电量没能达到1万亿EU/t的里程碑
不要害怕
这是硅岩燃料的终点
但它仍然未来可期
随着燃料的升级
我们几乎可以达到2万亿EU/t发电
现在我们有了更多的电力
我们着手完成新任务
在快速做完常规的部件后
我们可能想升级部件装配线
以降低时空和海珀珍成本
然而
看来我们不缺硬质金属
我们缺少外星细菌制造的聚合物
要跳过整个化学过程
我们需要四级量子操纵者
然而，这需要太多的UMV组件
所以我们回到超净间
在这变异更多细菌
然后放入新的培养缸
同时
我们可以生产一些高级材料
给电路装配加一步
我们得到了最后的UMV组件
然后我们制造新的超导
来做新的能源仓
能源仓现在可以做无线版本了
想得到它
全阶段的无线仓都得做一遍
让我们先停下，回到梦开始的地方
首先
我们需要新的超导
这次包含龙血和时空
使其超导
氦气已经落伍
必须使用时空
但这样只能做出普通的UMV能源仓
使其无线化
除了一堆昂贵的东西
我们需要做一些研究
非常套娃的研究
一直到ULV无线能量仓
尽管我们有UMV能源仓
我们没有ULV的
一旦我们得到它
我们必须研究和制作所有其他电压的能源仓
一路到UMV
由于我们的数据库插槽有限
我们懒得做第二个
我们把所有没用的东西都装进箱子里
现在它几乎满了
然后没有更多套娃
我们就获得了迄今最强的无线能源仓
64A UMV无线能源仓
它和16,384A UV激光源仓一样强力
但它是无线的
它的第一个用途是加速电路生产
这样我们就可以每分钟制造一个以上的UXV电路
而不是每15分钟一个
同时
我们升级了部件装配线
下一个任务不是真正的任务
而是一个警告
我们可以简单地把它标记为完成然后继续前进
但我认为我们应该升级基地
确实，从现在开始
要做一些戴森球还很困难
这可不是好消息
我们首先要解决的是拉多X聚合物
我们的主要目标是用QFT来生产它
但那需要四级外壳
第三级的我们都不好做
所以拉多X的旧产线必须扩大
幸亏有洛基戒指
我们可以同时制造许多机器
现在我们只需要再等一会儿
来存储拉多X
四级QFT需要的另一个材料是
超固态超能硅岩黑体
这是在超能硅岩的处理中产生的
这个过程输出一些惰性硅岩粉
数量可能看起来不大
但我们可以用中子活化器将其扩展成数千锭
转换的唯一成本是一点等离子体和时间
我们可以通过增加中子活化器的高度来缩短时间
因此，我们让它突破天际
三级QFT已经完成
要做四级的
我们需要更多的拉多X聚合物
在它囤积的同时
我们可以收集缺少的其他材料
我们的旧太空电梯无法储存足够的液体
所以我们升级了它的加速轨道和泵
虽然这很容易解决缺失的液体
但缺矿问题却不会改善
有些矿石不能通过太空开采获得
所以我们必须回到虚采
但我们想把它们放在更特别的地方
只有像我们这种真正的中二病才会选的地方
要到达那个地方
我们得从压缩大量圆石开始
聚爆必须升级
升级至时空块和使用80亿EU
才能在合理的时间内压缩圆石
我们将圆石涂上奶酪
这将充当其他组件的胶水
终于
我们用魔法把一些奇点粘在凝集物上
有了那个
我们现在可以去到应许之地
在那里虚采可以采掘出所有NEI里有的矿物
我们将其与矿处子网进行连接
开始开采这些材料
同时我们已经完成了四级QFT
它现在正在制造大量的拉多X聚合物
既然拉多X已不再是问题
我们终于可以开始制作10个戴森球的小工程了
然而
我们现在的基地无法应付那个微不足道的任务
我们必须做一些升级
首先要升级的是高炉
一些材料
每秒只能产出四个锭
积压的工作真的很多
所以进去检查后
我们决定采取的最佳行动
是给线圈加一些闪光
以及加点电进去
现在它的工作速度快了8倍
接下来要加速的是聚变反应堆
MK3一直很慢
MK4忙着做亚稳态鿫
所以我们要做Mk5聚变反应堆
你可以从它的颜色中看出它强得可怕
而且它确实跟10个MK 4的效率差不多
对于快速配方
我们可以手动设置并行
因此它比MK3快100倍
接下来是空冷塔
我们让PCB工厂加快2000倍
然后是纳米锻炉
我们建造了更多这样的建筑
同时也增加了工作功率
最终是我们的DTPF
我们又加了四个
但所有这些都导致了电力消耗的巨大增加
为了升级硅岩发电
我们添加两种液体
来提高燃料效率
这些液体是通过在锻造锤上
用超立方体和量子反常来撕裂时空获得
这一提升足以让我们完成最后一个蓝搅拌配方
从而在我们耗尽燃料之前
建成新发电机
旧戴森球占用了相当大的空间
所以我们新设计一种紧凑的方案
我们发现可以共享一堆零件
最重要的是算力输入
我们现在将使其无线化
与云端连接
这样我们就能把计算机留在主基地规划好的数据中心
有了那个设置
我们现在正在产生更多的能量
但对于升级后的基地也只是堪堪满足
所以很明显我们需要更多
但是有一个主要问题
我们生产转转锭的速度太慢了
EBF每秒都生产不了两个
而需要的数量以百万计
抱着找到解法的希望
我们应该去求助一些随机的村民
他们似乎在崇拜一些随机的神
看来我们的祈祷得到了回应
我们要做的就是建造一个致敬神的锻炉
我们要把它做大一点
并且比我们迄今为止构建的任何其他多方块都更复杂
制作它
我们要搜索无法找到的粒子
生产像出bug了的奇怪材料
合成出抽象玩意
一旦所有收集部分完成
我们就把各种机器都灌满
来大量制作各式各样的东西
我们可以快速烧制老东西
但是得慢慢处理那些
一个戴森球才供得起的耐烧王们
但给予足够的时间
我们设法处理了所有这些东西
并完成我们的锻炉
这东西不仅外观大得出奇
内部也别有洞天
我们首先要读的是华丽介绍
它解释了这台机器是如何工作的
但我们最关心的是
是通往天体超越的道路
这将帮助我们升级锻炉
更进一步
如果我们想让它可用
我们必须从头开始
进行此升级
我们需要一些额外的材料
我们很快收集好并交付
完成第一次升级
完成后
我们现在可以添加第一个模块
太阳烈焰能量锻炉
这个模块将像高炉一样工作
现在一切都建成了
是时候开机了
为此
我们制造一些恒星燃料
将其放入锻炉
然后我们提供超维度残留供其运行
现在可以欣赏神锻旋转
但它仍未达到辉煌的顶峰
我们可以让里面的恒星更加明亮多彩
我想我们现在可以花一分钟来欣赏新机器
但这并不是它的最终形态
但是获得进化将是一件更复杂的事情
所以让我们从使用拥有的模块开始
我们发现这已经比得上八个巨高炉了
当该模块工作时
我们实际上正在增加锻造里程碑的进度
这些目标一旦达成将奖励我们引力子碎片
可用于更多升级
在做完所有基本升级后
我们面临第一个重要升级
这个还需要一些额外的材料
其中之一是无损光子传输介质
长话短说
我们需要达到一个高于普通高炉所能达到的温度
17000K
甚至太阳烈焰能量锻炉都达不到
但我们可以提高神锻的燃料效率
来达到更高的温度
现在我们可以制作这些材料
我们遇到了另一个问题
我们没有足够的铜
但我们可以用太空电梯来挖
大部分的铜
都用于生产六相铜纳米蜂群了
虽然这部分所需材料需要大量的铜
还有一件事反而需要很多时间
超时空纳米蜂群
所以我们可以利用这段时间建造更多的纳米锻炉
有了这个
我们解锁了太阳射流融化核心
这个模块会把矿粉直接融化成液体
无需真空冷冻机和流体提取器
有了这两个模块
旧高炉可以退休了
那会回收很多方块
并摧毁我们牢不可破的工具
但其实不难造
不管怎样
我们可以做的下一次升级是
引力等离子体约束感应器
这将解锁太阳热能等离子制造机
那东西能把任何东西变成等离子
对于我们使用的大部分等离子来说
这东西并不值得
但在生产那些稀缺材料
和聚变产量低的材料时有大用
这也是以后获得一些特殊等离子的唯一手段
终于
我们解锁了太阳聚变异化器
但这只能在下一电压使用
现在我们处于分叉口
我们只能选择三条路径中的一条
当我们决定走哪条路时
我们可以做最后一个QFT
这将移除大量产线
这让我们做了大量的清扫工作
并重构我们的整个基地
再也没有凌乱的电缆了
最后
我们添加了更多戴森球
增加我们的发电量
有了这个
我想我们终于可以结束这一集了
那么今天的教训是什么？
如果你想凝视太阳
墨镜可不够格
你需要一些专门的设备
最好是个焊接头盔
拜拜
（量子操纵者，Quantum Force Transformer, QFT）
（edgelord：网络用语，带点调侃/贬义。指那些刻意装酷、装神秘、装黑暗的人，常常表现得很“前卫”“叛逆”，但其实有点做作）
（漆黑世界，Deep Dark, DD）